Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have a
lesson that comes
actually from a user request.
That's right. We had a
user request who asked us
if we can do something
about a purchasing manager,
maybe what his job does or what
it is to be a purchasing manager.
So you'll find out all about
that today in this lesson.
It's an upper intermediate about being
a purchasing manager and about vendor.
So let's check out today's dialogue.
Good morning Angela.
How have you been lately?
Morning Michael.
I've been very busy lately.
One of our other vendors
is going out of business
and I've been searching
for a suitable replacement.
Well rest assured that
you can count on us to be
here for the long run.
Please sit down. Coffee?
No thanks. I've been trying
to cut down on the caffeine.
I could never do that. I'd be a zombie
if I didn't have my morning coffee fix.
Let's get down to business then.
Yes. I've come to talk with you
about ordering the eight megapixel
cameras for a new methane.
The demand for phone
cameras is growing and
a pair has been falling
behind in the market.
That's great. I'm glad to hear that pair
has finally jumped on the bandwagon.
Right now our contract is
for the five megapixel cameras.
Is pair still interested
in having those?
No. We're changing all the
cameras to eight megapixels.
We were hoping that by
making your company our sole
supplier for cameras we
could negotiate a better deal.
Surely. Let's get started
by drafting a new contract.
All right we're back. So a very
interesting job to be a purchasing manager.
A lot of responsibility on top
of him and we actually saw some
really interesting phrases and
words that are related to business.
Negotiating contracts,
etc. So let's take a
look at some of those
now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first where we have is vendor.
This is a noun. It means it's a job.
It's the name of a person's job.
So he is a vendor.
Okay. And a vendor? What does a vendor do?
Well, a vendor
sells things. Okay.
So the verb here is to
"vend" like a vending machine.
That machine that
you can buy sodas from.
But a vendor is someone who
sells things to someone else.
Okay. So I can say he is a door vendor.
He sells doors?
Yeah. That's right. Or let me contact my
vendor about the price list for these TVs.
Okay. Very good. So we're talking about
a vendor who is going out of business.
And because he's going
out of business, this manager
is actually looking for
a suitable replacement.
So this is an interesting phrase because
these two words normally go together.
We say, let's find a
replacement. Okay.
That's good. But really, we
want a suitable replacement.
And so first of all, the word suitable
means like appropriate or good.
But what about replacement?
What does this mean?
A replacement is something that takes
the place of it replaces something else.
So for example, we have a
vendor who went out of business.
So what we are looking now for is
another vendor, but not just any vendor.
A suitable vendor, one that has the things
that we need or the prices that we need.
And in order to replace the
one that went out of business.
Right. So because it is about
other things, not just people.
For example, if I break my iPhone,
my cell phone, very expensive phone,
I'm upset about it. But when I buy
a new one, I don't want a cheap one.
I want a suitable replacement.
One that's about the same as the old one.
That's right. So you may
maybe you don't get the
exact same one, but you
get one that's very similar.
Exactly. Okay. Very
good. So now they're
going to talk a little
bit about the contract.
But they kind of do a little bit of small
talk and they're talking about coffee.
And he says, well, you know, I'd be a zombie
if I didn't have my morning coffee fix.
I know how that feels. This is a person
who loves to drink caffeine to wake up.
And so we talk about a fix as
being something that you need. Okay.
My coffee fix means the coffee
that I drink in the morning to survive.
That's right. Okay. So
we know the verb to
fix is to make something
good again to repair.
But in this case, we're
taking fix as a noun and
we're saying that it's
something that you need.
Like you said, for example,
maybe in the morning, you
need your English fix and
so you'd listen to English pod.
Exactly. You need it so much.
It's like a drug.
That's right. Very good. And
moving on, they started to
talk a little bit more about
the details of the business.
And he mentioned that
they want to make this
company there's sole
supplier for cameras.
Okay. So soul SLE means
only, but this word supplier is
very interesting because
it's very similar to vendor.
So it's basically someone
a company maybe or
a person that supplies
you with what you need.
All right. So to supply is to
provide for. So for example, if
I work at a clothing store
and I sell lots of nice clothing,
I need a supplier to bring
me the clothes that I sell.
Otherwise, where am I going to
get them from? I don't have a factory.
That's right. For example,
IBM is one of the biggest
computer suppliers or
manufacturers in the world.
All right. Okay. And for
the last part of the dialogue,
they said, well, I think we
can reach an agreement.
Let's get started by
drafting a new contract.
They're going to
draft a contract.
All right. So this is interesting because
we don't use the verb to write a contract.
Now you would think, well,
of course you write it, but
there's a special verb that
we use with the word contract.
So just remember this phrase
together to draft a contract
or my company will draft a
contract and send it to you.
This means to prepare a contract
in order for someone to sign it.
That's right. So it's basically
the same as right, but
it's usually used more with
contracts to draft a contract.
Exactly. Or maybe you can
say to draft up a business plan.
Exactly. So to draft a plan to
draft a contract, this is basically to
write something that has many different
points, many different strategies.
Okay. Very good. So five
key words for you there.
Now let's move on to some
key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay. So there are a lot of really,
really juicy phrases in today's lesson.
The first one is rest
assured. So we heard this
from Michael at the
beginning of the dialogue.
He said rest assured
that you can count on us.
That's right. Rest assured. So this is
a phrase that you use to try to give
confidence to someone telling them you can
trust me rest assured that I'll be there.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
So let's hear
another example of it.
Rest assured Marco, I will
be there to support you.
Okay. So I know that
you will be there or I can
trust that you'll be
there. Okay. Very good.
So to rest assured.
Now the second part of
it is in that same sentence,
we'll rest assured that
you can count on us.
Okay. So what does it mean
to count on us to count on me?
So the word to count has a couple
of different meanings and we're
most of us are familiar with
the other one to count numbers.
One, two, three, four, five, but here
to count on someone, remember that
proposition on, means to expect someone
to do something, to depend on someone.
That's right. So if you count
on someone means that you
depend on them, you rely
on them. You can trust them.
So for example, in the sentence
that I just told Marco, rest assured,
I will be there. You can count on me.
That means you can depend on me.
You can expect me to be there.
I will not let you down.
That's right. Okay. In that same sentence,
we have another phrasal verb, rest
assured that you can count on us to
be here for the long run, the long run.
All right. So we're not
actually running here.
The long run is a phrase
that means for a long time.
So for example, if I'm in an interview and someone
asks me, well, we're really interested in your
resume and we really like you, we want to know,
are you available in the long run in the long term?
That's right. So if you say, yes, I am here for the long run,
it means that you are here for a long time. Okay. And let's move
on to our next phrase, when they're actually, you know, they
stopped with a small talk and now they want to get down to business.
You hear this phrase all the time because
you don't just walk into a meeting and
start talking about business stuff. You
know, you start with the nice things first.
You say, how is your weekend? How is your wife? How is that
game of golf? So you're talking about nice small talk, like you
just said Marco, but when you want to start talking about
numbers or products, things like that, that is called business.
So when you want to start that, you say, let's get
down to business. That's right. Very good. So it's a
phrase to say, okay, now let's start talking about what
we came here to do, the start talking about business.
And the last phrase that we have for you, it's a very
interesting phrase. When they were talking about one
of the brands of phones, they're saying, I'm glad to
hear that pair has finally jumped on the bandwagon.
Now Marco, I wish I could tell you I knew where
this phrase came from, but I don't. Let's just
talk about the word bandwagon first. I think
bandwagon means something that everyone is doing.
And all of a sudden you like the color purple, then that means you just
jumped on the bandwagon. All right, I jumped on the bandwagon. So you
think of a wagon is like, you know, before the head cars, they have
wagons, they're wooden and they have wheels and they're pulled by a horse.
And so everyone is on there and they're all
going somewhere. And I wasn't done it, but
I jumped on the back. That means I joined
everyone. I started to do what they are doing.
That's right. So I guess you agree with them or
you're going towards in the same direction that
everyone else is going. Look at Marco, he just
bought an iPhone. Now he's jumped on the bandwagon.
That's right. So everyone is going in the
same direction. Everyone is doing the same
thing. Everyone likes the same thing. So
to jump on the bandwagon, you can use it.
In the business sense, for example, if somebody's not
agreeing with you or somebody doesn't want to support
your project, you can say, I would really appreciate it
if you jumped on the bandwagon and supported us on this.
That's right. So it's
not always a bad thing.
But remember that the verb that is
synonymous with this is to conform.
Okay. To do what everyone
else is doing. That's right. Okay.
So a lot of interesting things here.
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
Good morning, Angela.
How have you been lately?
Morning, Michael. I've been very
busy lately. One of our other vendors is
going out of business and I've been
searching for a suitable replacement.
Well, rest assured that you can
count on us to be here for the long run.
Please sit down. Coffee? No, thanks. I've
been trying to cut down on the caffeine.
I could never do that. I'd
be a zombie if I didn't have
my morning coffee fix. Let's
get down to business then.
Yes. I've come to talk
with you about ordering
the eight megapixel
cameras for a new methane.
The demand for phone cameras is growing and
Pear has been falling behind in the market.
That's great. I'm glad to hear that Pear has
finally jumped on the bandwagon. Right now
our contract is for the five megapixel cameras.
Is Pear still interested in having those?
No. We're changing all the cameras to
eight megapixels. We were hoping that by
making your company our sole supplier for
cameras, we could negotiate a better deal.
Surely. Let's get started
by drafting a new contract.
So, talking about purchasing, it's actually a very interesting
position. I think many, almost all companies, big companies have
this position where not only do they have to maybe if they're in
retelling, they have to purchase the goods that they will sell.
But also in offices, for
example, who buys the paper,
the printers, the copiers,
everything for the office.
That's right. And this is a
very important position, as you
say, because this person can
save a company a lot of money.
If the person knows the right vendors, that's
right. If the only vendors you know are
selling things at very high prices, then that's
not very good for you or for your business.
But if you know all the inside
secrets, you know all the good
vendors, then maybe you're going
to be able to save a lot of money.
That's right. So I think this position
is also a lot broader than just this.
So maybe someone can also help us
out on the website, EnglishPod.com.
You can explain, maybe if you're a
purchasing manager, you can tell us what
your job entails, or if you know a
purchasing manager, what does that person do?
That's right. We're very curious to know.
And we hope that you'll be able to use some
of these new words and phrases. If you want
to practice, check us out, EnglishPod.com.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.